<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <title>Sustainability in the Making</title>
    <link href="https://sustainabilityinthemaking.com/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://sustainabilityinthemaking.com" />
    <updated>2024-02-19T13:13:04+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Alessandra Fasoli</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://sustainabilityinthemaking.com</id>

    <entry>
        <title>EthnoGraphics: a graphic mixed-method for studying cultures</title>
        <author>
            <name>Alessandra Fasoli</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://sustainabilityinthemaking.com/ethnographics-research/"/>
        <id>https://sustainabilityinthemaking.com/ethnographics-research/</id>
        <media:content url="https://sustainabilityinthemaking.com/media/posts/24/ethnographics-cover.webp" medium="image" />
            <category term="research"/>
            <category term="methodology "/>
            <category term="Hero"/>
            <category term="EthnoGraphics"/>

        <updated>2024-02-19T13:13:04+00:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://sustainabilityinthemaking.com/media/posts/24/ethnographics-cover.webp" alt="digital watercolour drawing of sketchbooks and pens " />
                    EthnoGRAPHICS is the methodology underpinning the work of this research. It plays with the word "ethnography" and "graphics", because&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://sustainabilityinthemaking.com/media/posts/24/ethnographics-cover.webp" class="type:primaryImage" alt="digital watercolour drawing of sketchbooks and pens " /></p>
                
  <p>
    EthnoGRAPHICS is the methodology underpinning the work of this research. It plays with the word "ethnography" and "graphics", because it uses graphics languages and elements — like sketches, drawings, comics, and infographics — to collect and show data. 
<br>EthnoGRAPHICS is a is a mixed-method ethnographic approach to study cultural dynamics generated during craft-led events focused on sustainability. It combines:
  </p>

  <ul>
    <li>graphic ethnography 
</li><li>oral history 
</li><li>an online space for showcasing and resources</li>
  </ul>

  <p>
    EthnoGRAPHICS aims to observe, describe, and understand how engaging with sustainable making allows people to reflect and learn about the environment, the climate crisis, consumerism, and production. 
<br>
<br>The graphic ethnography approach is based on <b>observational sketching</b>, a participant observation activity where drawing and sketches are the researcher’s primary method of notetaking and data gathering. 
<br>
<br>The oral history approach comprises <b>semi-structured interviews</b> with organisers and facilitators of craft initiatives and <b>spontaneous conversations</b> with participants in the programmes’ events. 
<br>
<br>The online space is a<b> website</b> — that you are visiting right now by reading this page —  build along as the research progresses to showcase and narration of the findings. This is meant to be a<b> virtual home of the project</b>, where participants and visitors can see the progress of the research in the Galleries section. A Resources in the Making is a work-in-progress space for anyone who visit it to engage with the initiatives presented or find inspiration and guides for starting their own.
<br>
<br>This website and the methodology page are updated regularly.&nbsp;
  </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Sustainability in the Making: Craft Programmes for Eco-Social Change</title>
        <author>
            <name>Alessandra Fasoli</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://sustainabilityinthemaking.com/about/"/>
        <id>https://sustainabilityinthemaking.com/about/</id>
        <media:content url="https://sustainabilityinthemaking.com/media/posts/18/new-hero-2.webp" medium="image" />
            <category term="Hero"/>
            <category term="About"/>

        <updated>2024-02-13T20:00:19+00:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://sustainabilityinthemaking.com/media/posts/18/new-hero-2.webp" alt="decorative collage of sketches of people doing crafts and plants" />
                    Alessandra Fasoli © 2023. Ceramicist Sarah Sullivan performing at the Green Maker Initiative Spring Event, Make Southwest. Sustainability in&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://sustainabilityinthemaking.com/media/posts/18/new-hero-2.webp" class="type:primaryImage" alt="decorative collage of sketches of people doing crafts and plants" /></p>
                
    <figure class="post__image post__image--center">
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://sustainabilityinthemaking.com/media/posts/18/sarah-sullivan-performing-at-make-southwest.webp" height="1632" width="1793" alt="Watercolour drawing of a woman making pottery. "  sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" srcset="https://sustainabilityinthemaking.com/media/posts/18/responsive/sarah-sullivan-performing-at-make-southwest-xs.webp 300w ,https://sustainabilityinthemaking.com/media/posts/18/responsive/sarah-sullivan-performing-at-make-southwest-sm.webp 480w ,https://sustainabilityinthemaking.com/media/posts/18/responsive/sarah-sullivan-performing-at-make-southwest-md.webp 768w ,https://sustainabilityinthemaking.com/media/posts/18/responsive/sarah-sullivan-performing-at-make-southwest-xl.webp 1200w ,https://sustainabilityinthemaking.com/media/posts/18/responsive/sarah-sullivan-performing-at-make-southwest-xxl.webp 1600w ,https://sustainabilityinthemaking.com/media/posts/18/responsive/sarah-sullivan-performing-at-make-southwest-xxxl.webp 1920w">
      <figcaption>Alessandra Fasoli © 2023. Ceramicist Sarah Sullivan performing at the Green Maker Initiative Spring Event, Make Southwest.</figcaption>
    </figure>

  <p>
    Sustainability in the Making is a PhD project that explores how craft and making contribute in building cultures of sustainability. 
<br>Cultures of sustainability are collective systems of knowledge and customs rooted in environmental and ecological values, which allow both individuals and communities to adopt more environmentally-friendly behaviours, lifestyles, and norms.
<br>Many studies on sustainable craft focus on the way makers embody sustainability in their creative process: for example how they use recycled or upcycled materials, create artefacts using local resources, or make objects with specific sustainable purposes. This PhD, however, looks at sustainable craft from a different perspective, which sees craft and making as social activities through which people share, transform, and create cultural values, like preserving traditions, building local identities, sharing worldviews, creating a sense of place or collective histories.
  </p>

    <figure class="post__image post__image--center">
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://sustainabilityinthemaking.com/media/posts/18/heritage-craft-bovey-tracey-1.webp" height="2149" width="1608" alt="Watercolour and ink drawing of a man weaving a willow basket"  sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" srcset="https://sustainabilityinthemaking.com/media/posts/18/responsive/heritage-craft-bovey-tracey-1-xs.webp 300w ,https://sustainabilityinthemaking.com/media/posts/18/responsive/heritage-craft-bovey-tracey-1-sm.webp 480w ,https://sustainabilityinthemaking.com/media/posts/18/responsive/heritage-craft-bovey-tracey-1-md.webp 768w ,https://sustainabilityinthemaking.com/media/posts/18/responsive/heritage-craft-bovey-tracey-1-xl.webp 1200w ,https://sustainabilityinthemaking.com/media/posts/18/responsive/heritage-craft-bovey-tracey-1-xxl.webp 1600w ,https://sustainabilityinthemaking.com/media/posts/18/responsive/heritage-craft-bovey-tracey-1-xxxl.webp 1920w">
      <figcaption>Alessandra Fasoli © 2023. Man weaving a willow basket at the Heritage Craft Pavilion at Craft Festival Bovey Tracey 2023</figcaption>
    </figure>

  <p>
    By connecting this definition of sustainable craft with cultures of sustainability, this PhD asks if and how craft can be a vehicle to build sustainability cultures and aims to answer this question by studying existing craft programmes that promote specific environmental, ecological, and sustainable approaches through making.
  </p>

    <h2 id="brief-background-story-from-lessigreatercraft-in-makerspaceslessigreater-to-lessigreatersustainability-in-the-makinglessigreater">
      Brief Background Story: from <i>Craft in Makerspaces</i> to <i>Sustainability in the Making</i>
    </h2>

  <p>
    This PhD started in 2019, with the title <em>Craft in Makerspaces: the Potential for Social Change for Sustainability</em>, inspired by various initiatives in the making that in the second decade of the 2000s were crossing borders between traditional craft practices and the more tech-based maker movement. 
<br>However, my preliminary research in the Devon area pushed me towards a rethinking of my makerspace-based approach to this research, as diverse definitions and approaches of craft for sustainability started to emerge. Maker craft communities in Devon and the Southwest are fluid, active, and resilient communities, whose connection with the territory runs deep.  I decided then to take a broader social and cultural perspective, which led to the current title and approach&nbsp;<em>Sustainability in the Making: Craft Programmes for Socio-Ecological Change</em>.&nbsp;It looks more broadly at craft-led sustainability initiatives and programmes in the Southwest, which may or may not be also makerspace-based or makerspace-driven. 
  </p>

    <figure class="post__image post__image--center">
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://sustainabilityinthemaking.com/media/posts/18/makerspace.webp" height="1079" width="1417" alt="Digital drawing of people working in a makerspace"  sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" srcset="https://sustainabilityinthemaking.com/media/posts/18/responsive/makerspace-xs.webp 300w ,https://sustainabilityinthemaking.com/media/posts/18/responsive/makerspace-sm.webp 480w ,https://sustainabilityinthemaking.com/media/posts/18/responsive/makerspace-md.webp 768w ,https://sustainabilityinthemaking.com/media/posts/18/responsive/makerspace-xl.webp 1200w ,https://sustainabilityinthemaking.com/media/posts/18/responsive/makerspace-xxl.webp 1600w ,https://sustainabilityinthemaking.com/media/posts/18/responsive/makerspace-xxxl.webp 1920w">
      <figcaption>Alessandra Fasoli © 2020. Makerspace. Original drawing.</figcaption>
    </figure>

  <p>
    If you are more curious about the history and evolution of <i>Sustainability in the Making</i> project and want to know about it more in depth, go to the project <a href="https://sustainabilityinthemaking.com/tags/research-road-map/">Road Map</a>: a detailed timeline with writings, studies, and graphics produced along the way.
  </p>

  <p>
    
  </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Craft, Sustainability, and Makerspaces: a Brief Intro to my Research</title>
        <author>
            <name>Alessandra Fasoli</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://sustainabilityinthemaking.com/craft-sustainability-and-makerspaces-a-brief-intro-to-my-research/"/>
        <id>https://sustainabilityinthemaking.com/craft-sustainability-and-makerspaces-a-brief-intro-to-my-research/</id>
        <media:content url="https://sustainabilityinthemaking.com/media/posts/12/craft-in-makerspaces_loom_web.jpg" medium="image" />
            <category term="Research Road Map"/>
            <category term="About"/>

        <updated>2023-10-21T17:26:34+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://sustainabilityinthemaking.com/media/posts/12/craft-in-makerspaces_loom_web.jpg" alt="Vector drawing of a woman with a child seated in front of a loom. The vertical textile shows maker tools as woven into the fabric " />
                    In 2019, I started a PhD on craft for sustainable behaviour at Kingston School of Art London. Craft in&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://sustainabilityinthemaking.com/media/posts/12/craft-in-makerspaces_loom_web.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Vector drawing of a woman with a child seated in front of a loom. The vertical textile shows maker tools as woven into the fabric " /></p>
                <p>In 2019, I started a PhD on craft for sustainable behaviour at <u><a href="https://www.kingston.ac.uk/faculties/kingston-school-of-art/">Kingston School of Art London</a></u>.
<em>Craft in Makerspaces: The Potential for Social Change for Sustainability</em> (working title) is an <a href="http://www.techne.ac.uk/for-students/techne-students/techne-students/techne-students-2019-20/fasoli">AHRC-funded project</a> done in partnership with the <a href="https://www.craftscouncil.org.uk/">Crafts Council</a>. It explores how cultures of making contribute to social sustainability and aims to gain insights for community craft-led initiatives to be actively integrated in sustainability policies. </p>
<p>This research expands <a href="https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/14606925.2017.1352819">my previous studies about the social role of makerspaces</a>, sometimes called hackerspaces or fab labs, which are a network of community open workshops that emerged and spread globally since the 2000s. Their dissemination generated a maker movement based on sharing tools, knowledge, and practices. Although they might not have an explicit sustainability mission, makerspace communities promote DIY practices, repairability, recycling, and reuse of objects, while the adoption of digital fabrication technologies like 3d printing or CNC milling machines led to the concept of <em><a href="https://www.nesta.org.uk/blog/the-factory-everywhere-the-present-and-future-of-distributed-manufacturing/">distributed manufacturing</a></em>, which advocates for a more local and custom production of objects.<br>Being often described as revolutionary and breakthrough, these approaches focus on products and production by answering the questions on <em>how</em> and <em>where</em> things are made, but leave aside <em>why</em> and <em>what</em> things are made, that instead inquiry the cultural significance of artefacts. Culture plays a crucial role in sustainability, as they inform behaviours, consumers’ choices, and production systems. In mass manufactured products and production, cultural values are mostly hidden: like for example, in a cheap sweater. They however become evident in craft objects, like a hand-knitted jumper by your mum, where the value of the family relationship is transferred and embedded in the jumper, and the time, care, and inventiveness in creating it give to the artefact a special meaning.</p>
<p>Craft practices have then retained a cultural affection and reconnect us with the material world in a more direct, sometimes nostalgic, way. <a href="https://www.craftscouncil.org.uk/learning/participation/what-we-learned-from-co-creating-in-makerspaces">Makerspaces gave craft a new opportunity</a> to claim back its social dimension through public engagement in making, increased using digital platforms. In both physical and digital maker communities it is the practice of making, not artefacts, that is shaping and strengthening the relationship between the members of these communities, and between communities and their environment. Considering its shared cultural value, craft can then be an important tool to create sustainability cultures. </p>
<p>After a first stage of exploring the cultural meaning of craft, makerspaces, and social sustainability, my project is now investigating what <em>craft in makerspaces</em> means for communities in Devon, where I live, and where there is an active sustainability-oriented maker tradition. This is a participatory process through which the local maker communities are actively helping me to build a map of Devon making ecologies and understand how they are contributing to enhance a social sustainable behaviour. 
However, for craft practices to have a meaningful impact in building environmental cultures, they need to be integrated into more structural sustainability strategies. The final goal of this project is to have an outcome that points in this direction, a toolkit for stakeholders to promote and improve craft-led sustainability change.</p>
<p><em>A <a href="https://www.craftscouncil.org.uk/about/research-and-policy/march-2022/craft-in-makerspaces">shorter version</a> of this article has been featured in the Crafts Council’s Research Updates in March 2022.</em></p>

            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Design Culture(s) | Cumulus Rome 2021</title>
        <author>
            <name>Alessandra Fasoli</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://sustainabilityinthemaking.com/hero/"/>
        <id>https://sustainabilityinthemaking.com/hero/</id>
        <media:content url="https://sustainabilityinthemaking.com/media/posts/9/Craft-in-Makerspaces_cover.jpg" medium="image" />
            <category term="Research Road Map"/>

        <updated>2023-10-03T15:54:15+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://sustainabilityinthemaking.com/media/posts/9/Craft-in-Makerspaces_cover.jpg" alt="digital drawing of a human figure making a pottery sculpture with the help of a big robot arm. " />
                     Poster: “Craft in Makerspaces: The Potential for Social Change for Sustainability” Sapienza University of Rome In June 2021, I&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://sustainabilityinthemaking.com/media/posts/9/Craft-in-Makerspaces_cover.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="digital drawing of a human figure making a pottery sculpture with the help of a big robot arm. " /></p>
                <h2 class="align-center"> Poster: “Craft in Makerspaces: The Potential for Social Change for Sustainability”</h2>
<p class="align-center">Sapienza University of Rome</p>
<p class="align-center">In June 2021, I announced my research at the <a href="https://cumulusroma2020.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Cumulus Conference 2021 "Design Culture(s)</a>", hosted by Sapienza University of Rome. At the time of the call for papers (2019, the conference originally was planned in 2020, but it was postponed due to COVID-19 pandemic), my research was at a very early stages. The very first poster I submitted was still very vague in its approach, but as in 2020 I definitely move to the UK, I decided to focus the research on the observation of local maker communities. Because of health restrictions in place in 2021, I attended the conference online, where I presented my early plans for my research in the dedicated poster section. </p>
<hr>
<p class="align-center">To cite this work:</p>
<p class="sqsrte-small align-center">Fasoli, A. (2021) ‘Craft in Makerspaces: The Potential for Social Change for Sustainability', [Poster], in Di Lucchio, L. et al. (eds) Design Culture(s). Cumulus Conference Proceedings Roma 2021, Volume #2. Design Culture(s), Rome (Cumulus Conference Proceedings Series, N°7), p. 4773.</p>
<hr>
<figure class="post__image post__image--center"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://sustainabilityinthemaking.com/media/posts/9/Fasoli_Cumulus_MAKING_2020_camera-ready.jpg" alt="Poster for the Cumulus Conference Rome 2021 &quot;Design Culture(s)&quot;" width="2834" height="5669" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" srcset="https://sustainabilityinthemaking.com/media/posts/9/responsive/Fasoli_Cumulus_MAKING_2020_camera-ready-xs.webp 300w ,https://sustainabilityinthemaking.com/media/posts/9/responsive/Fasoli_Cumulus_MAKING_2020_camera-ready-sm.webp 480w ,https://sustainabilityinthemaking.com/media/posts/9/responsive/Fasoli_Cumulus_MAKING_2020_camera-ready-md.webp 768w ,https://sustainabilityinthemaking.com/media/posts/9/responsive/Fasoli_Cumulus_MAKING_2020_camera-ready-xl.webp 1200w ,https://sustainabilityinthemaking.com/media/posts/9/responsive/Fasoli_Cumulus_MAKING_2020_camera-ready-xxl.webp 1600w ,https://sustainabilityinthemaking.com/media/posts/9/responsive/Fasoli_Cumulus_MAKING_2020_camera-ready-xxxl.webp 1920w"></figure>
<p>The proceedings of the conferences are available for download at <a href="https://cumulusroma2020.org/proceedings/">https://cumulusroma2020.org/proceedings/</a></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
